<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Writing</title><link href="http://blog.sitongpeng.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.sitongpeng.com/feeds/2016.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.sitongpeng.com/</id><updated>2016-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Dear Toronto,</title><link href="http://blog.sitongpeng.com/posts/dear-toronto.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-01-08T12:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Sitong Peng</name></author><id>tag:blog.sitongpeng.com,2016-01-08:posts/dear-toronto.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have a few things to say to the people I met in a city I wasn't sure I would like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Toronto at night" src="https://raw.github.com/stoneG/stoneg.github.com/master/images/toronto.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&lt;/strong&gt;, the pakistani man who makes butter chicken roti at your strangely NYC themed restaurant, who passably decorated it by throwing up old LIFE magazine covers on the walls, who has family trouble in California and a cousin doing a stint in our penal system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&lt;/strong&gt;, the pupusa lady that gave me an extra tamale on the house after I had such a hard time deciding which pupusas and tamale flavors I wanted to try, who then laughed when I immediately came back to order the fried plantains, which I saw while waiting for my order (they weren't on the menu I agonized over).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&lt;/strong&gt;, the guy bumping to &lt;em&gt;Hotline Bling&lt;/em&gt; outside your car that I grooved with, but politely had to decline your offer of a cigarette, because I had gone through D.A.R.E. three times as a kid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&lt;/strong&gt;, the roommate who was once a kingpin of street fighter arcade sticks as well as an elite Canadian memory champion, who is unfazed by face transplant images that made me jump out of my chair, who upon learning I was leaving Toronto without seeing Niagara Falls rented a car and drove us out there at midnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&lt;/strong&gt;, the roommate who is a sound mixing engineer that did a tour of duty in Nashville but somehow managed to work on rock instead of country, who showed me the process for modern sound mixing using Britney Spears’ &lt;em&gt;I'm a Slave For You&lt;/em&gt; (dozens of vocal tracks!), who stood in the hallway with me until 3am because we had delved too deep into our opinions about movies &amp;amp; games for sleep to matter anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&lt;/strong&gt;, the roommate who is polyglot that’s lived in many different countries, who works harder to balancing work and school than most anyone I've met, who still had the energy to unabashedly start dancing the one time I casually panned you into my snapchat video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&lt;/strong&gt;, the girl with an excitement that is palpable, contagious, and hard to forget, who unquestioningly shared your hopes and dreams to a complete stranger who slid into your DMs, who despite living there your whole life, seemed somehow less familiar with directions in Toronto than me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&lt;/strong&gt;, the guy who has not ventured out of Montreal for over 35 years, but gave me change for the bus and humored me while I chatted you up about how your city's bagels had ruined me for life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You all made me feel odd, like I was leaving a place that had become a home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confused in California.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="travel"></category><category term="toronto"></category></entry><entry><title>Coming up in 2016</title><link href="http://blog.sitongpeng.com/posts/coming-up-in-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-01-06T20:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Sitong Peng</name></author><id>tag:blog.sitongpeng.com,2016-01-06:posts/coming-up-in-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a few years since I’ve done this &lt;a href="/posts/programming-resolutions.html"&gt;publicly&lt;/a&gt;, but I’d like to bring this tradition back. Learning from past experiences, I’m keeping this list concise and specific. Life can sometimes get in the way but here’s what I’m agreeing to in 2016:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship something in virtual reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write 8 posts worthy of reading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hike at two national parks, preferably new.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live in a foreign country that's new to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a fluidity in the kitchen so most dishes I make are served on time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be able to name all common herbs &amp;amp; spices by sight &amp;amp; smell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accomplish at least two physical goals for surfing, snowboarding, skiing, or weightlifting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time's ticking.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="resolutions"></category><category term="2016"></category></entry><entry><title>Refocusing</title><link href="http://blog.sitongpeng.com/posts/refocusing.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-01-06T01:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Sitong Peng</name></author><id>tag:blog.sitongpeng.com,2016-01-06:posts/refocusing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before I release the 2016 ones, here are my last set of resolutions from &lt;a href="/posts/programming-resolutions.html"&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="quote"&gt;"100 posts about programming things I’ve encountered and want to share"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rode the new years train a bit too hard on this one. Even without life getting in the way, this would have been a tough one to keep, but glad I managed even 14 posts even if 13 came in the first half of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="quote"&gt;"Contribute a couple patches or a bug fix to an open source project."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my credit, I did make a very small contribution to Django REST Framework as well as other smaller repositories. Work and personal projects have always gotten the best of me. I’ve since forked projects and made features I’ve needed but I’ve always been too lazy to properly submit pull requests with tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="quote"&gt;"Do a weekend project and get it on the front page of HN"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, it seems silly to make a project with the explicit intention of making the HN front page. No wonder this is the resolution I remember making the least. I suspect many developers have fallen into the same trap, but I have numerous projects that are anywhere from 50% to 80% complete. Shipping products is an art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="quote"&gt;“Read more books: I need to expand my knowledge beyond just reading the news and blogs"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By my count, I’ve read around 18 books since then. Paltry, to be sure, but not nothing.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="resolutions"></category></entry></feed>