<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Writing</title><link href="http://blog.sitongpeng.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.sitongpeng.com/feeds/2017.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.sitongpeng.com/</id><updated>2017-01-02T21:30:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Resolving 2016</title><link href="http://blog.sitongpeng.com/posts/resolving-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2017-01-02T21:30:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Sitong Peng</name></author><id>tag:blog.sitongpeng.com,2017-01-02:posts/resolving-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Let's go over my 2016 &lt;a href="/posts/coming-up-in-2016.html"&gt;resolutions&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="quote"&gt;"Ship something in virtual reality"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a scene in VR but nothing worth sharing or shipping. This resolution fell to the wayside since I was waiting for the touch controllers to come out. I also started some work on a 2D project. I might prefer 2D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="quote"&gt;"Write 8 posts worthy of reading"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it sure is rough to have fallen short on the first two resolutions. This one was related to the first, as I was planning on writing about things I learned in VR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="quote"&gt;"Hike at two national parks, preferably new"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiked at Arches, Joshua Tree, Banff, Mt. Rainier, Crater Lake. Each park was deeply inspiring in its own way and I continue to feel lucky and humbled upon every visit. To get a feel for what I saw, check out my &lt;a href="https://instagram.com/stoneG"&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="quote"&gt;“Live in a foreign country that's new to me"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent March living in Budapest. I had an amazing time in that city. Solo travel has shown me how much I care about human relationships. So it's exceedingly ironic that where I expected to find independence, I instead found how I crave the vulnerability of dependence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="quote"&gt;“Develop a fluidity in the kitchen so most dishes I make are served on time"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prepared somewhere between one to two handfuls of multiple course dinner parties (~6 people each time). And most were ready to go by the time the last guest arrived!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="quote"&gt;Be able to name all common herbs &amp; spices by sight &amp; smell"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBD, I need to test myself and get this on tape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="quote"&gt;"Accomplish at least two physical goals for surfing, snowboarding, skiing, or weightlifting"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Surfing&lt;/em&gt;: After many youtube videos and lots of trial and error, I'm proud to say I can usually get up on the board, albeit sometimes only briefly before falling. I still need to work on my speed and foot placement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Snowboarding&lt;/em&gt;: I definitely progressed from beginner/intermediate to intermediate/advanced levels. I’m good enough to mess around on jumps at the terrain park and I can get some good speed on downhill runs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bonus physical goal&lt;/em&gt;: I went from the couch to a half marathon this year :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;All in all: 4 to 5 resolutions of 7.&lt;/h2&gt;</summary><category term="resolutions"></category></entry></feed>